<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>By the Mayor, to the Alderman of the Ward of [blank] whereas by an ordinance entitled, an ordinance for the better amending and keeping in repaire the common high-wayes within this nation ...</title>
            <author>Corporation of London (England). Lord Mayor.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1654</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 4 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 1 1-bit group-IV TIFF page image.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2014-11">2014-11 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">B09427</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing L2883FA</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R179975</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">61297075</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocm 61297075</idno>
            <idno type="VID">180613</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. B09427)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 180613)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English Books, 1641-1700 ; 2837:13)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>By the Mayor, to the Alderman of the Ward of [blank] whereas by an ordinance entitled, an ordinance for the better amending and keeping in repaire the common high-wayes within this nation ...</title>
                  <author>Corporation of London (England). Lord Mayor.</author>
                  <author>Vyner, Thomas, Sir, 1588-1665.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>1 sheet ([1] p.).   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printed by James Flesher,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[London] :</pubPlace>
                  <date>[1654]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Caption title.</note>
                  <note>Form letter.</note>
                  <note>At end: "Dated this 25th of April 1654."</note>
                  <note>Title vignette: City of London coat of arms.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in: Bodleian Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>London (England) --  History --  17th century.</term>
               <term>Roads --  England --  Maintenance and repair --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Road construction --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Great Britain --  History --  Commonwealth and Protectorate, 1649-1660.</term>
               <term>Broadsides --  England --  17th century.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2013-05</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-07</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-11</date>
            <label>Colm MacCrossan</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-11</date>
            <label>Colm MacCrossan</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-03</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="proclamation">
            <pb facs="tcp:180613:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <head>
               <figure>
                  <figDesc>blazon or coat of arms of the City of London</figDesc>
               </figure> By the Mayor.</head>
            <opener>
               <salute>
                  <hi>To the Alderman of the Ward of <gap reason="blank" resp="#OXF" extent="1 word">
                        <desc> _____ </desc>
                     </gap> 
                  </hi>
               </salute>
            </opener>
            <p>
               <seg rend="decorInit">W</seg>Hereas by an Ordinance entituled, <hi>An Ordinance for the better amending and keep<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing in repaire the common High-wayes within this Nation:</hi> It is ordained amongſt other things that in every Pariſh within this Nation of <hi>England and Wales</hi> there be two or more (according to the greatneſſe of the Pariſhes) able and ſufficient Houſeholders inhabiting in ſuch Pariſh, yearely elected and choſen to be Surveyors for amending High-wayes, Streets and Pavements, within their re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſpetive Pariſhes the firſt <hi>Tueſday</hi> next enſueing the twenty fifth of <hi>March</hi> yearely, under the penalty of Twenty pounds to be forfeited by the Pariſhoners of ſuch Pariſh where no ſuch Surveyors ſhall be choſen as aforeſaid, who being choſen are to accept of the ſaid place, and be ſworne, as is appointed by the ſaid Ordinance, after ſuch election, under the penalty therein contained; Streets and pavements being thereby declared to be common High-waies, and Scavengers to be Surveyors, within the intent and conſtruction of the ſaid Ordinance and within all Lawes in force concerning Highwayes, And whereas by a latter Ordinance of the twelfth of <hi>April 1654</hi> the time for election of ſuch officers this preſent yeare is appointed to be before the firſt day of <hi>May</hi> next, and ſworne on or before the firſt of <hi>May</hi> aforeſaid, under the penalties aforeſaid, as by the ſaid ſeveral Ordinances may appeare: In perſuance thereof, and to the intent that all perſons concerned therein may be carefull to performe what on their part is to be obſerved, and that a more full reformation may be had and made, then formerly in the paving and cleanſing the ſtreets and in the channells and watercourſes within this City and liberties thereof. Theſe are therefore in the name of his Highneſſe the <hi>Lord Protector, of England, Scotland, and Ireland,</hi> to will and require you that preſently upon ſight hereof you ſend directions with a coppie of this precept to every pariſh within your ward, That the Scavengers now in being and other Houſe-holders inhabiting in their reſpective pariſhes rated to the poore doe before the firſt day of <hi>May</hi> now next enſuing choſe two or more according to the greatneſſe of their ſaid pariſhes to be Scavengers accor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ding to the true intent and meaning of the ſaid ſeverall Ordinances, and for the purpoſes therein contained, to the end they may be ſworne in due time and proceed in the due execution of the premiſes: And that on or before the ſaid firſt day of <hi>May</hi> you cauſe certificate in writing to be made unto me of the names of all ſuch perſons as ſhall be choſen Scavengers, and the ſeverall pariſhes for which they ſhall be ſo choſen, And herein you are not to fayle.</p>
            <closer>
               <dateline>
                  <hi>Dated</hi> 
                  <date>this 25<hi rend="sup">th</hi> of Aprill 1654.</date>
               </dateline>
               <signed>Sadler.</signed>
            </closer>
         </div>
      </body>
      <back>
         <div type="colophon">
            <p>Printed by <hi>James Fleſher,</hi> Printer to the Honourable City of LONDON.</p>
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>
